{"componentChunkName":"component---src-templates-establishment-page-js","path":"/establishment/51622570","result":{"data":{"site":{"pathPrefix":"/restaurant-inspections"},"postgres":{"establishment":[{"establishmentid":"51622570","name":"Avalon Cafe and Biscuit Bar","address":"2998 W. Grand Blvd.","zipcode":"48202","owner":"Jackie Victor","licenseNumber":"220234","licenseType":"Fixed Establishment","establishmentType":"Food Service Establishment","establishmentStatus":"Permanently Closed","riskCategory":"High","reviewFrequencyDays":"150","coords":"-83.07692,42.36844","geojson":{"id":"51622570","type":"Feature","geometry":{"type":"Point","coordinates":[-83.076921356,42.36843854]},"properties":{"name":"Avalon Cafe and Biscuit Bar","owner":"Jackie Victor","address":"2998 W. Grand Blvd.","zipcode":"48202","license_type":"Fixed Establishment","risk_category":"High","license_number":"220234","establishmentid":"51622570","establishment_type":"Food Service Establishment","establishment_status":"Permanently Closed","review_frequency_days":"150","most_recent_license_date":"2020-04-22"}},"nearbyList":[{"establishmentid":"4170","name":"New Center Park","address":"2998 Grand Blvd. W.","zipcode":"48202"},{"establishmentid":"4878","name":"Cafe Con Leche - Nord","address":"2990 W. Grand Blvd","zipcode":"48202"},{"establishmentid":"662","name":"Northern Lights Lounge","address":"660 Baltimore St. W.","zipcode":"48202"},{"establishmentid":"2984","name":"Michigan Commission for the Blind","address":"3060 Grand Blvd. W.","zipcode":"48202"},{"establishmentid":"2316","name":"Mr. Pita","address":"3031 GRAND BLVD UNIT #202 W.","zipcode":"48202"},{"establishmentid":"1861","name":"The Blend II","address":"3044 Grand Blvd. W.","zipcode":"48202"},{"establishmentid":"1712","name":"JCE Acquisitions, LLC  DBA Subway ","address":"3044 Grand Blvd. W.","zipcode":"48202"},{"establishmentid":"3627","name":"The Coffee Shop & Deli","address":"3044 Grand Blvd. W.","zipcode":"48202"},{"establishmentid":"51622872","name":"Runabout Cafe","address":"3044 Grand Blvd. W.","zipcode":"48202"},{"establishmentid":"2287","name":"Lunchtime Neo LLC","address":"3031 Grand Blvd. W.","zipcode":"48202"}],"inspectionsByEstablishmentidList":[{"inspectionid":"53221","inspectionDate":"2020-10-28T00:00:00","inspectionType":"COVID19-temp closed","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[]},{"inspectionid":"53194","inspectionDate":"2020-10-22T00:00:00","inspectionType":"COVID19-temp closed","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[]},{"inspectionid":"51536","inspectionDate":"2020-03-30T00:00:00","inspectionType":"COVID19-temp closed","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[]},{"inspectionid":"50043","inspectionDate":"2019-12-01T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"6-301.12","violationDescription":"Each HANDWASHING SINK or group of adjacent HANDWASHING SINKS shall be provided with:\n(A) Individual, disposable towels; (Pf)\n(B) A continuous towel system that supplies the user with a clean towel;(Pf) or \n(C) A heated-air hand drying device.(Pf)\n(D) A hand drying device that employs an air-knife system that delivers high velocity pressurized air at ambient temperatures.(Pf)\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Sanitary hand drying provisions","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"At hand sink","location":"BACK AREA","subLocation":"At the Handsink","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2019-12-02T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide"},{"violationCode":"5-205.11","violationDescription":"(A) A HANDWASHING SINK shall be maintained so that it is accessible at all times for EMPLOYEE use and used for no other purpose. (Pf)\n(B)  An automatic handwashing facility shall be used in accordance with manufacturer's instructions. (Pf)\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Handwashing sink(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not accessible","subProblem":"","location":"HANDSINK(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2019-12-02T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"2-402.11","violationDescription":"FOOD EMPLOYEES shall wear hair restraints such as hats, hair coverings or nets, beard restraints, and clothing that covers body hair, that are designed and worn to effectively keep their hair from contacting exposed FOOD; clean EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, and LINENS; or unwrapped SINGLE-SERVICE or SINGLE-USE ARTICLES.","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Hair restraint","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not worn on head/hair","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":"2019-12-02T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null}]},{"inspectionid":"48258","inspectionDate":"2019-07-02T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"6-301.12","violationDescription":"Each HANDWASHING SINK or group of adjacent HANDWASHING SINKS shall be provided with:\n(A) Individual, disposable towels; (Pf)\n(B) A continuous towel system that supplies the user with a clean towel;(Pf) or \n(C) A heated-air hand drying device.(Pf)\n(D) A hand drying device that employs an air-knife system that delivers high velocity pressurized air at ambient temperatures.(Pf)\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Sanitary hand drying provisions","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"At hand sink","location":"BACK AREA","subLocation":"At the Handsink","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2019-07-03T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide"}]},{"inspectionid":"44995","inspectionDate":"2019-01-27T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"3-501.19","violationDescription":"If time only, rather than time in conjunction with temperature, is used as the public health control for a working supply of POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  before cooking, or for READY-TO-EAT, POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  that is displayed or held for service for immediate consumption:   \n(1)   Written procedures are required to be prepared in advance, maintained in the establishment, and made available to the REGULATORY AUTHORITY upon request.(Pf)\n(2)   The FOOD shall be marked to indicate the time that is 4 hrs past the point in which food is removed from temperature control, or 6 hrs if the temperature is maintained below 70Â°F. (Pf)\n(3)   Food in unmarked containers or in containers that exceed the time limit are to be discarded. (P)\n        \n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Time controlled food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Without time control mark","subProblem":"Indicating time that is 4 hours past removal from temperature control","location":"SANDWICH STATION","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2019-01-28T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide clear easy to read time marks."},{"violationCode":"4-302.14","violationDescription":"A test kit or other device that accurately measures the concentration in mg/L of SANITIZING solutions shall be provided. (Pf)\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Sanitizer test kit","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"ESTABLISHMENT","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2019-02-21T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide."},{"violationCode":"4-204.112","violationDescription":"(A)  In a mechanically refrigerated or hot FOOD storage unit, the sensor of a TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICE shall be located to measure the air temperature in the warmest part of a mechanically refrigerated unit and in the coolest part of a hot FOOD storage unit.\n(B)  Cold or hot holding EQUIPMENT used for POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD shall be designed to include and shall be equipped with at least one integral or permanently affixed TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICE that is located to allow easy viewing of the device's temperature display (EXCEPT, heat lamps, cold plates, steam tables, or other equipment where it is not practical).\n(C)  TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICES shall be designed to be easily readable.\n(D)  FOOD TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICES and water TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICES on WAREWASHING machines shall have a numerical scale, printed record, or digital readout in increments no greater than 1C or 2F in the intended range of use. (Pf)\n\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Thermometer(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Reach-in cooler","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2019-02-21T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Install to meet requirements"},{"violationCode":"6-301.12","violationDescription":"Each HANDWASHING SINK or group of adjacent HANDWASHING SINKS shall be provided with:\n(A) Individual, disposable towels; (Pf)\n(B) A continuous towel system that supplies the user with a clean towel;(Pf) or \n(C) A heated-air hand drying device.(Pf)\n(D) A hand drying device that employs an air-knife system that delivers high velocity pressurized air at ambient temperatures.(Pf)\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Sanitary hand drying provisions","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"At hand sink","location":"BACK AREA","subLocation":"At the Handsink","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2019-01-28T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide"},{"violationCode":"MFL289.4119","violationDescription":"Sec. 4119. (1) Except as otherwise provided in subsection (2), a person licensed as a food establishment under this chapter shall keep a copy of the current license or temporary license furnished by the department posted and exposed in a conspicuous place for public inspection. A conspicuous place is the principal place where food business is transacted.  (2) In the case of vending machines, the name and address and telephone number of the current vending machine location operator shall be conspicuously displayed on each vending machine.","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Food Service License","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not displayed","subProblem":"","location":"ESTABLISHMENT","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":""},{"violationCode":"MFL289.2129","violationDescription":"Sec. 2129. (1) All food establishments shall employ a minimum of 1 managerial employee as a food safety manager, who must be an individual who is currently certified under a personnel certification program accredited by the American National Standards Institute, utilizing the Conference for Food Protection standards:\n(2) Beginning January 14, 2017 and every 5 years thereafter, a certified  food safety manager who supervises the operations of a food service establishment shall have completed a food safety training program\ncontaining an allergen awareness  component that has been approved by  the department. A food service establishment shall retain records on the  site of the food service establishment documenting compliance of its  certified food safety managers with this subsection. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Person-in-charge","subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"ESTABLISHMENT","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null}]},{"inspectionid":"43201","inspectionDate":"2018-06-14T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"3-501.17","violationDescription":"(A)  READY-TO-EAT, POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  prepared and held refrigerated for more than 24 hours in a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT  shall be clearly marked at the time of preparation to indicate the date or day by which the FOOD shall be consumed. (Pf)\n(B)  A container of refrigerated, commercially prepared READY-TO-EAT POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  shall be clearly marked, at the time the original container is opened in a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT, to indicate the date or day by which the FOOD shall be consumed. (Pf)\n\nA date marking system that does not exceed 7 days, including date of preparation, or opening is to be used. (Pf)\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"In house prepared ready-to-eat potentially hazardous  food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Without date of consumption marking","subProblem":"","location":"FRONT COUNTER/AREA","subLocation":"In the Reach-in cooler","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2018-06-15T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Datemark with a discard date of 7 days or less."},{"violationCode":"6-301.12","violationDescription":"Each HANDWASHING SINK or group of adjacent HANDWASHING SINKS shall be provided with:\n(A) Individual, disposable towels; (Pf)\n(B) A continuous towel system that supplies the user with a clean towel;(Pf) or \n(C) A heated-air hand drying device.(Pf)\n(D) A hand drying device that employs an air-knife system that delivers high velocity pressurized air at ambient temperatures.(Pf)\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Sanitary hand drying provisions","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"At hand sink","location":"BACK AREA","subLocation":"At the Handsink","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2018-06-15T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide"},{"violationCode":"3-501.15","violationDescription":"(A) Cooling shall be accomplished in accordance with the time and temperature criteria specified under Â§ 3-501.14 by using one or more of the following methods based on the type of FOOD being cooled:  \n   (1) Placing the FOOD in shallow pans; (Pf)\n   (2) Separating the FOOD into smaller or thinner portions; (Pf)\n   (3) Using rapid cooling EQUIPMENT; (Pf)\n   (4) Stirring the FOOD in a container placed in an ice water bath; (Pf)\n   (5) Using containers that facilitate heat transfer; (Pf)\n   (6) Adding ice as an ingredient; (Pf) or\n   (7) Other effective methods. (Pf)  \n(B) When placed in cooling or cold holding EQUIPMENT, FOOD containers in which FOOD is being cooled shall be:  \n   (1) Arranged in the EQUIPMENT to provide maximum heat transfer through the       container walls; and\n   (2) Loosely covered, or uncovered if protected from overhead contamination as          specified under Subparagraph 3-305.11(A)(2), during the cooling period to facilitate    heat transfer from the surface of the FOOD.","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Food item(s) cooled","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Improperly","subProblem":"Nested on top each other","location":"FRONT PREP AREA","subLocation":"In the Reach-in cooler","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2018-06-15T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Do not nest pans."},{"violationCode":"MFL289.4119","violationDescription":"Sec. 4119. (1) Except as otherwise provided in subsection (2), a person licensed as a food establishment under this chapter shall keep a copy of the current license or temporary license furnished by the department posted and exposed in a conspicuous place for public inspection. A conspicuous place is the principal place where food business is transacted.  (2) In the case of vending machines, the name and address and telephone number of the current vending machine location operator shall be conspicuously displayed on each vending machine.","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Food Service License","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not displayed","subProblem":"","location":"ESTABLISHMENT","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":""},{"violationCode":"6-501.12","violationDescription":"(A) PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean.\n(B) Except spill cleanup, cleaning shall be done during periods when the least amount of FOOD is exposed such as after closing. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Physical facilities/structures","subItem":"floors","problemDescription":"With accumulation of debris","subProblem":"","location":"FRONT PREP AREA","subLocation":"Under the Equipment","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Keep clean."},{"violationCode":"MFL289.2129","violationDescription":"Sec. 2129. (1) All food establishments shall employ a minimum of 1 managerial employee as a food safety manager, who must be an individual who is currently certified under a personnel certification program accredited by the American National Standards Institute, utilizing the Conference for Food Protection standards:\n(2) Beginning January 14, 2017 and every 5 years thereafter, a certified  food safety manager who supervises the operations of a food service establishment shall have completed a food safety training program\ncontaining an allergen awareness  component that has been approved by  the department. A food service establishment shall retain records on the  site of the food service establishment documenting compliance of its  certified food safety managers with this subsection. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Person-in-charge","subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"ESTABLISHMENT","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null}]},{"inspectionid":"40479","inspectionDate":"2017-10-18T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"3-304.15","violationDescription":"(A) SINGLE-USE gloves shall be used for one task only and discarded when      damaged, soiled, or when interruptions occur in the operation. (P)\n\n(B) Slash-resistant and cloth gloves shall be used in direct contact only with FOOD that is subsequently cooked. Gloves used with ready-to-eat foods shall be smooth,   durable and non-absorbant.\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2017-10-19T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"3-501.18","violationDescription":"A FOOD specified in Â¶ 3-501.17(A) or (B) shall be discarded if it:  \n    (1) Exceeds the temperature and time combination specified in Â¶ 3-501.17(A),              except time that the product is frozen; (P)\n    (2) Is in a container or PACKAGE that does not bear a date or day; (P) or\n    (3) Is appropriately marked with a date or day that exceeds a temperature and              time combination as specified in Â¶ 3-501.17(A). (P)  \n\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2017-10-19T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"4-601.11","violationDescription":"(A) EQUIPMENT FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be clean to sight and touch. (Pf)\n(B) The FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of cooking EQUIPMENT and pans shall be kept free of encrusted grease deposits and other soil accumulations. \n(C) NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be kept free of an accumulation of dust, dirt, FOOD residue, and other debris. \n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2017-10-19T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"3-501.17","violationDescription":"(A)  READY-TO-EAT, POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  prepared and held refrigerated for more than 24 hours in a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT  shall be clearly marked at the time of preparation to indicate the date or day by which the FOOD shall be consumed. (Pf)\n(B)  A container of refrigerated, commercially prepared READY-TO-EAT POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  shall be clearly marked, at the time the original container is opened in a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT, to indicate the date or day by which the FOOD shall be consumed. (Pf)\n\nA date marking system that does not exceed 7 days, including date of preparation, or opening is to be used. (Pf)\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2017-10-19T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"3-305.14","violationDescription":"During preparation, unPACKAGED FOOD shall be protected from environmental sources of contamination.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"MFL289.2129","violationDescription":"Sec. 2129. (1) All food establishments shall employ a minimum of 1 managerial employee as a food safety manager, who must be an individual who is currently certified under a personnel certification program accredited by the American National Standards Institute, utilizing the Conference for Food Protection standards:\n(2) Beginning January 14, 2017 and every 5 years thereafter, a certified  food safety manager who supervises the operations of a food service establishment shall have completed a food safety training program\ncontaining an allergen awareness  component that has been approved by  the department. A food service establishment shall retain records on the  site of the food service establishment documenting compliance of its  certified food safety managers with this subsection. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"","subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null}]},{"inspectionid":"40107","inspectionDate":"2017-08-22T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Plan Review/Pre-Open","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"3-306.11","violationDescription":"Except for nuts in the shell and whole, raw fruits and vegetables that are intended for hulling, peeling, or washing by the CONSUMER before consumption, FOOD on display shall be protected from contamination by the use of PACKAGING; counter, service line, or salad bar FOOD guards; display cases; or other effective means. (P)\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Food on display","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Lacking protection","subProblem":"Sneeze guards","location":"SERVICE AREA","subLocation":"Sneeze Guard","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2017-08-25T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Protect against contamination"},{"violationCode":"4-903.11","violationDescription":"Cleaned EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS, laundered LINENS, and SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES shall be stored in an approved manner and location.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Clean equipment/utensil(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Exposed to dust, splash, or other contaminates","subProblem":"","location":"HANDSINK(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":"2017-08-25T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store in manner that does not contaminate items"}]}]}],"maxInspectionDate":[{"inspectionDate":"2023-04-25T00:00:00"}]}},"pageContext":{"eid":"51622570"}},"staticQueryHashes":["3649515864","63159454"]}